<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: non-technical | Greg Eng]]></title>
  <link href="http://gregeng.github.io/blog/categories/non-technical/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gregeng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T20:41:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://gregeng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Greg Eng]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[greg.eng@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Keep Climbing...]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregeng.github.io/blog/2013/09/29/just-keep-climbing/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-29T20:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregeng.github.io/blog/2013/09/29/just-keep-climbing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been one week since the semester began. In that short time span there have been highs, lows, and countless lines of code mistakes in between. Each night I leave feeling drained. At times, I have been concerned that I might not be keeping pace with my classmates. Still, each morning I wake up energized looking forward to get to school.</p>

<p>In a class-wide retrospective dubbed &ldquo;Feeling Friday&rdquo;, I learned that my peers have the same worries. Avi wisely mitigated our concerns by offering some perspective. He assured us that as long as we are constantly exploring, practicing and trying&hellip; we would be just fine. He went on to explain that the high and lows are just factors of learning in general. Each peak represents the gratification that comes directly after learning something new. Each low is just a representation <em>trying</em> to learn something new.</p>

<p>Suddenly, pace is irrelevant. We&rsquo;re all on this journey <em>with</em> and not <em>against</em> each other. The peaks and valleys may come at different points for different people but they <strong>will</strong> come. The ascent can sometimes be arduous but it is often mostly just fun. The view from the top is extremely enticing.</p>

<p>That elusive feeling of elation is what keeps me coming back. I can&rsquo;t wait to hit that next peak.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://gregeng.github.io/blog/2013/09/24/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-24T21:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://gregeng.github.io/blog/2013/09/24/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Hello World</em> &ndash; I&rsquo;ve written that simple phrase out so many times during the exercises in the Flatiron School <a href="http://prework.flatironschool.com/" target="_blank">prework</a>.  However, this time it&rsquo;s different. It certainly feels good to finally say that to something other than the terminal or console.</p>

<p>Over the course of this semester, I&rsquo;ll be blogging about my learning experience at the Flatiron School. I&rsquo;ll do my best to explain some of the topics we cover in order to help and inspire other hopeful developers. Thank you in advance for reading!</p>

<p>And just so we&rsquo;re acquainted, you should know I&rsquo;ve decided to become a web developer because &hellip;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been an Internet consumer since before AOL <a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/15030603/aol-cd.jpeg" target="_blank">discs</a> ever came in metallic cases. The dial-up connection crescendo still echoes in my mind. Throughout my life web technology has always made things better and easier. Dropbox helped me collaborate on group projects in school. YouTube taught me how to use Excel for my career in finance. I worked for an online dating startup that simply could not exist without it. Now I&rsquo;m motivated to do more than consume by learning how to code. I hope to pay my love for the web forward with the things that I make in the future.</p>

<p>So again, hello world and hello readers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
